PERSONAL INFORMATION

Full name LU HONG HAI (JASON)

Date of birth: March 17th, 1988

Nationality: Vietnam

Email: luhonghai@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/luhonghai

Github: https://github.com/luhonghai

Telephone: +84 (0) 986 899 787

Address: WBD1217, Westbay Tower D, Ecopark, Xuan Quan

Commune, Van Giang District, Hung Yen Province,

Vietnam

Current Occupation: Technical Lead - Backend Python/Java



BRIEF INFORMATION

A technical lead - backend Python/Java developer. Broad understanding and in-depth experience in architecture design, database design, API design and development. Strong at object-oriented programming (OOP) and DevOps.

Focus to microservices architecture, auto scaling and load balancing by using Kubernetes and Docker.

Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery for both frontend and backend.

Cloud computing with Google Cloud and Amazon Web Service.

Interested in big data, machine learning, blockchain, decentralized applications development (Ethereum, EOS).

Good command of English.

Strong in researching, analyzing, presentation, documentation, training and teamwork skills.

EDUCATION

2006 - 2011 Hanoi University of Science and Technology Hanoi, Vietnam

Faculty of Mathematics and Computer Science

2009 – 2013 FPT Aptech Hanoi, Vietnam

Software Engineering

SKILLS

Issue tracking: Atlassian Jira.

DevOps Kubernetes, Docker, Fastlane, NSQ, RabbitMQ, ELK, Graphite, Sentry

Framework Django, Flask

Continuous Integration: Jenkins (primary), Travis.

Version control: Git (primary), SVN.

Operate system: Mac OS X (primary), Linux, Windows.

Programing language: Python, Java, Javascript (ES6), Golang

Database: MySQL, Oracle, SQLite, MongoDB.

WORKING EXPERIENCES

2016 - Present Mobile Health Vietnam Hanoi, Vietnam

Position: Technical Lead - Backend Python/Golang

Job Description: - Architecture design

- Django/Flask/Python development and code review

- Golang code review

- DevOps , setup CI & CD by using Jenkins, Fastlane, Fabric, Docker,

Kubernetes

- R&D, estimation, documentation, training ...

Projects - MaNaDr platform - A massive healthcare ecosystem https://

www.manadr.xyz/

2015 - 2016 Claybourne McGregor (C-MG) Hanoi, Vietnam

Position: Senior Java/Python Developer

Job Description: Lead, design, develop and maintain accenteasy® Administration server,

accenteasy® Android and accenteasy® iOS application.

Projects - accenteasy® - Machine learning and natural language processing

(NLP) company accenteasy shared their expertise with Education Ministers on their 2020 English language project. The aim of Project 2020 is to improve English language standards in Singapore, Malaysia

and Vietnam by 2020.

2011 - 2014 Claybourne McGregor (C-MG) Hanoi, Vietnam

Position: Java Developer

Job Description: Maintain BP Pensionline system and develop new system for BP from the

beginning of 2012 called BP Pablo.

Lead, develop and maintain a training requirements mapping automation

tool for BP Upstream.

Write document, setup and guide team to apply Continuous Integration process, move from SVN to Git, upgrade Issus tracking system and build

tool (Jira, Bamboo, Github).

Investigate and apply Amazon Web Service, Machine learning, Digital signal processing for pronunciation application called accenteasy®.

Work on some projects use Google Cloud Computing (Google App

Engine), Android and iOS application.